<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<mods xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
    xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3 http://www.loc.gov/standards/mods/v3/mods-3-5.xsd">
    <identifier>JFKWHP/1962/jackAndBobby</identifier>
    <titleInfo>
        <title>President John F. Kennedy and Attorney General Robert F. Kennedy</title>
        <partNumber>ST-423-2-62</partNumber>
    </titleInfo>
    <originInfo>
        <dateCaptured>3 October 1962</dateCaptured>
        <publisher>John F. Kennedy Library (Boston, MA) Contact: John F. Kennedy Library (NLJFK), Columbia Point, Boston, MA 02125-3398 Phone: 617-514-1600, Fax: 617-514-1652, Email: kennedy.library@nara.gov</publisher>
    </originInfo>
    <typeOfResource>still image</typeOfResource>
    <physicalDescription>
        <digitalOrigin>digitized other analog</digitalOrigin>
        <form>1 copy negative (black and white; 4x5 inches)</form>
        <note>Every effort has been made to digitize images in a way that accurately reflects the arrangement and condition of the original materials.  Scans were created using the most original source available, typically an original negative; if the original negative was not available, then the scan was made from an original file print, and if neither of these was available, then the scan was made from a copy negative. The digital image reflects the item's physical condition. Highlight/shadow points were optimized, and the unsharp mask filter was applied to compensate for the scan. Minor dusting and scratch repair and some color correction might have been done to compensate for the scan. No other alterations or enhancements were made to the scan. This digital file is an accurate representation of the image as held in the John F. Kennedy Presidential Library.</note>
    </physicalDescription>
    <subject>
        <topic>Kennedy, Robert F. (Robert Francis), 1925-1968</topic>
        <topic>Kennedy, John F. (John Fitzgerald), 1917-1963</topic>
        <topic>others?</topic>
    </subject>
    <recordInfo>
        <recordContentSource>Cecil Stoughton. White House Photographs. John F. Kennedy Presidential Library and Museum, Boston</recordContentSource>
    </recordInfo>
    <abstract>President John F. Kennedy meets with Attorney General Robert F. Kennedy (left) in the West Wing Colondade outside the Oval Office, White House, Washington D.C. The President and Attorney General both face away from camera; open door at right lead inside Oval Office.</abstract>
    <location>
        <physicalLocation>John F. Kennedy Presidential Library</physicalLocation>
    </location>
    <recordInfo>
        <recordIdentifier>ST-423-2-62</recordIdentifier>
        <recordCreationDate>2010-03-19</recordCreationDate>
    </recordInfo>
</mods>
