<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<mods xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
    xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3 http://www.loc.gov/standards/mods/v3/mods-3-5.xsd">
    <originInfo>
        <dateCreated>12 September 1962</dateCreated>
    </originInfo>
    <typeOfResource>text</typeOfResource>
    <abstract>This document details a very famous speech made my President John F. Kennedy at Rice University in Houston Texas concerning the importance of America's role in the space race.  In it, Kennedy lays out several points which detail why it is important for America to be at the forefront of this race and how these points are achievable with enough funding, energy, know-how, determination, and the right attitude.</abstract>
    <titleInfo>
        <title>Papers of John F. Kennedy</title>
        <title>Presidential Papers</title>
        <title>President's Office Files</title>
        <title>Speech Files</title>
        <title>Address at Rice University, Houston, Texas, 12 September 1962</title>
    </titleInfo>
    <identifier>JFKPOF/040/riceUniversity</identifier>
    <language>
        <languageTerm>English</languageTerm>
    </language>
    <subject>
        <genre>Presidential Speeches</genre>
        <topic>Cold war</topic>
        <topic>Space</topic>
        <topic>Rice University</topic>
    </subject>
    <physicalDescription>
        <digitalOrigin>digitized other analog</digitalOrigin>
        <note>This folder contains materials collected by the office of President John F. Kennedy's secretary, Evelyn Lincoln, concerning President Kennedy's remarks at the Rice University Stadium in Houston, Texas concerning the nation's efforts in space exploration. In his speech the President discusses the necessity for the United States to become an international leader in space exploration, and famously states, "We choose to go to the Moon in this decade and do the other things, not because they are easy, but because they are hard." Materials in this folder include a draft by Special Counsel and speechwriter Theodore Sorensen, press copies, and a reading copy of the speech. Of note are several items with handwritten notations by the President.</note>
    </physicalDescription>
    <originInfo>
        <publisher>John F. Kennedy Library (Boston, MA) Contact: John F. Kennedy Library (NLJFK), Columbia Point, Boston, MA 02125-3398 Phone: 617-514-1600, Fax: 617-514-1652, Email: kennedy.library@nara.gov</publisher>
        <dateOther>Scanned on: 2007-10-24</dateOther>
    </originInfo>
</mods>
